- Are you ready, kids?
- 孩子们，你们准备好了吗？
all:
Aye, aye, Captain!
全部：
是啊是啊，队长！
- I can't hear you.
- 我听不到你说话。
all:
Aye, aye, Captain!
全部：
是啊是啊，队长！
- * Ohh...
- * 哦...
* Who lives in a pineapple
under the sea? *
*谁住在菠萝里
在海底？ *
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
- * Absorbent and yellow
and porous is he *
- * 吸水性和黄色
他是多孔的*
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
- * If nautical nonsense
be something you wish *
- *如果航海废话
成为你所希望的*
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
- * Then drop on the deck
and flop like a fish *
- * 然后落在甲板上
然后像鱼一样扑通扑通 *
all: SpongeBob SquarePants!
- Ready?
所有：海绵宝宝！
- 准备好？
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
SpongeBob SquarePants!
- SpongeBob
- 海绵宝宝
SquarePants!
方裤！
[laughing]
[笑]
*
[waves crashing]
[海浪拍打]
[upbeat music]
[欢快的音乐]
*
- We interrupt this program
- 我们中断这个程序
to bring you
a Bikini Bottom News Flash.
给你带来
比基尼泳裤新闻快讯。
- [neighs]
- Whoa, big fella.
- [嘶嘶声]
- 哇，大家伙。
- Mr. Plankton,
we've received word
- 浮游生物先生，
我们已收到消息
that you're plotting
to infiltrate the Krusty Krab
你正在策划的
潜入蟹堡王
and steal the Krabby Patty
secret formula.
并偷走蟹黄饼
秘密配方。
Is that true?
这是真的吗？
- Actually, yes, that is true.
- 事实上，是的，确实如此。
I've got it all worked out.
我已经把一切都解决了。
First I break into the safe
and--ehh.
首先我闯入保险箱
还有——呃。
Wait, is this live?
等等，这是直播吗？
- Yes.
- 是的。
- Don't broadcast
my secret plans!
- 请勿广播
我的秘密计划！
They're secret!
他们是秘密的！
I will destroy
all of you!
我会摧毁
你们所有人！
[panting]
[气喘吁吁]
Secret formula, ho!
秘密配方，呵呵！
- [neighs]
- [嘶嘶声]
- I reckon that classified
taste mixture
- 我认为这属于机密
味道混合物
will be in my hands directly.
将直接在我手中。
[inhales]
[吸气]
[groans]
[呻吟]
Ow!
噢！
[laughs]
[笑]
The fool!
傻瓜！
He left the safe open.
他把保险箱打开了。
Open for business, baby!
开门营业了，宝贝！
[groans]
[呻吟]
- [laughs]
- [笑]
Gotcha.
明白了。
- [screaming]
- [尖叫]
- [laughs]
- [笑]
[suspenseful music]
[悬疑音乐]
*
I'm off to make a delivery.
我要去送货了
- Ha, that fool.
- 哈，那个傻瓜。
[groans]
[呻吟]
[panting]
[气喘吁吁]
And the Krabby Patty
is made of...
还有蟹黄饼
是由...制成的
urchins!
顽童！
- Ew! Ew!
- 呃！呃！
- Gotcha!
[laughs]
- 明白了！
[笑]
- [laughs maniacally]
- [疯狂地笑]
Yoink!
哟哟！
- Huh?
- 啊？
- [laughing]
Yes!
- [笑]
是的！
- Pull!
- 拉！
Yee-haw!
呀呀！
[laughs]
[笑]
- [screaming]
- [尖叫]
[propeller whirring]
[螺旋桨呼呼地响]
- [groans]
- Gotcha!
- [呻吟]
- 明白了！
[laughs]
[笑]
[mysterious music]
[神秘的音乐]
*
- [groaning]
- [呻吟]
[screaming]
[尖叫]
- [laughs]
Gotcha.
- [笑]
明白了。
- Alley-oop!
- 空中接力！
- [slurping]
- [发出声音]
[gulps, belches]
[吞咽，打嗝]
- Whee!
- 呼！
Come to daddy, patty!
到爸爸那里来吧，帕蒂！
[groans]
[呻吟]
[straining]
[紧张]
[laughs]
[笑]
- Gotcha.
- 明白了。
[laughs]
[笑]
- Eeh.
- 呃。
- [grumbling]
- [抱怨]
[yells]
[喊叫]
Oh, Karen,
he covered me in urchins,
哦，凯伦，
他用海胆覆盖我，
fed me to a seahorse,
and stung me to death.
把我喂给海马，
并把我蜇死了。
I fly through the air,
he flies through the air.
我在空中飞翔，
他在空中飞翔。
I hide in a stomach,
he hides in a stomach.
我躲在肚子里
他藏在肚子里。
I have had enough!
我已经受够了！
- Oh, I think someone needs
their ba-ba.
- 哦，我想有人需要
他们的爸爸。
There, isn't that better?
有了，那不是更好吗？
- No, Karen!
- 不，凯伦！
That's just not gonna
work anymore!
那只是不会
不再工作了！
Don't you see?
We're done here.
你没看到吗？
我们到这里就完成了。
- He said for
the 9 billionth time.
- 他说为了
第90亿次。
You know, Sheldon,
if I had a dime
你知道，谢尔顿，
如果我有一毛钱
for every time you--
[powers down]
每当你——
[断电]
[cricket chirping]
[蟋蟀鸣叫]
["Taps" plays]
[“点击”播放]
*
- Mr. Krabs,
did you see that?
- 蟹老板先生，
你看到了吗？
Plankton is retiring.
浮游生物即将退休。
- I'll believes it
when I sees it.
- 我会相信
当我看到它的时候。
- [whimpers]
- [呜咽]
- [grunts]
Hey, ha ha!
- [咕哝]
嘿嘿嘿！
All hands on deck,
SpongeBob!
所有人都在甲板上，
海绵宝宝！
Aye-aye, Mr--whoa!
是啊是啊，先生——哇！
Oh-oh-oh!
哦哦哦！
- [laughs]
- [笑]
- Aw, you want to say
good-bye to Plankton,
- 噢，你想说
再见浮游生物，
you old softy you.
你这个老软蛋。
- That'll be the day.
- 那一天就会到来。
I don't trust Plankton
as far as I throw him.
我不相信浮游生物
就我把他扔远了。
That's why we're gonna
shadow that little twit
这就是为什么我们要
影子那个小家伙
and find out what he's up to.
并找出他在做什么。
[groans]
[呻吟]
- "Welcome to Dullsville:
a charmingly boring--"
- “欢迎来到杜尔斯维尔：
令人着迷的无聊——”
- Snap your trap, boy-o.
You'll blow our cover.
- 拉开你的陷阱，小伙子。
你会暴露我们的掩护。
- A new life in a new town.
- 新城镇的新生活。
[laughs]
[笑]
- I still don't see Plankton
doing anything wrong.
- 我还是没有看到浮游生物
做任何错事。
Maybe he really is retiring.
也许他真的要退休了。
- Believes it
when I sees it.
- 相信它
当我看到它的时候。
- [humming]
- [嗡嗡声]
*
- Quick, boy,
he's getting away.
- 快点，男孩，
他要走了。
[both scream]
[两人尖叫]
- [humming]
- [嗡嗡声]
[bell dings]
[铃声]
- Yes?
- I'd like a room, please.
- 是的？
- 我想要一个房间。
- Very good, sir.
- [groans]
- 很好，先生。
- [呻吟]
- How long will you be
staying with us?
- 你会持续多久
和我们住在一起吗？
- [groaning]
- [grumbles]
- [呻吟]
- [抱怨]
Forever.
永远。
Ahhh!
啊啊！
[groaning]
[呻吟]
And so begins my retirement.
我的退休生活就这样开始了。
[laughs maniacally]
[疯狂地笑]
- You see you, lad.
Plankton is up to no good.
- 你看到你了，小伙子。
浮游生物不怀好意。
I bet those are all the fixings
for another evil lab.
我打赌这些就是所有的配件
另一个邪恶的实验室。
- Mr. Krabs,
I'm gonna be sick.
- 蟹老板先生，
我会生病的。
- [laughs]
- [笑]
Yes.
是的。
Yes!
是的！
- You see, he's got an evil belt
to match those evil shoes.
- 你看，他有一条邪恶的腰带
来搭配那些邪恶的鞋子。
- Yes!
- 是的！
My plan is almost complete.
我的计划快完成了。
[laughs maniacally]
[疯狂地笑]
- His plan!
Did you hear that, SpongeBob?
- 他的计划！
你听到了吗，海绵宝宝？
He said plan!
他说计划！
- Uh, please, don't shake me,
Mr. Krabs.
- 呃，请不要摇晃我，
蟹老板。
- Oh, my pretty.
- 哦，我的美人。
You'll be my best friend
from now on.
你会成为我最好的朋友
从现在开始。
[laughs]
[笑]
Retirement is mine.
退休是我的。
Mine.
矿。
Mine!
[laughs]
矿！
[笑]
- Ooh, this is it, boy-o.
- 哦，就是这样，男孩。
He's got an evil laser
death apparatus contraption
他有邪恶的激光
死亡装置装置
ready to spring on all of us.
准备好向我们所有人扑来。
- [laughs maniacally]
- [疯狂地笑]
[cheerful music]
[欢快的音乐]
- Ooh.
- 哦。
[both yell]
[两人大喊]
[grumbling]
[抱怨]
Now that I sees it,
I believes it.
现在我看到了，
我相信。
- Hurray! I knew you'd
get it, Mr. Krabs.
- 万岁！我就知道你会
明白了，蟹老板。
[retching]
[干呕]
- Krabs!
- 螃蟹！
What are you doing
in my hotel room?
你在做什么
在我的酒店房间里？
- [stammers]
- [结巴]
Oh.
哦。
Good luck on your retirement,
Plankton.
祝你退休生活好运，
浮游生物。
I won't give you
any more trouble.
我不会给你
还有什么麻烦吗。
- Oh, I know you won't, Krabs,
- 哦，我知道你不会的，蟹蟹，
because I'm at
the Krusty Krab right now
因为我在
蟹堡王现在
stealing that formula.
窃取那个公式。
- Oh-oh, sure.
Whatever you say, old-timer.
- 哦哦，当然。
不管你说什么，老前辈。
How would you be doing that when
you're all the way over here
当你这样做的时候你会怎么做
你就在这里
in Dullsville, hmm?
在杜尔斯维尔，嗯？
- [laughs]
- [笑]
Because I'm a decoy
look-alike robot!
因为我是一个诱饵
长得很像的机器人！
Gotcha!
[laughs]
明白了！
[笑]
- [sighs]
So what'd I miss?
- [叹气]
那么我错过了什么？
both: What?
两人：什么？
- That's right, Karen.
- 没错，凯伦。
By the time those two
knuckleheads figure it out,
到时候那两个人
傻瓜们想明白了
I'll be knee-deep
in secret formula.
我会齐膝深
在秘密公式中。
Yes, I'll wear my galoshes.
Gotta go.
是的，我会穿上套鞋。
得走了。
[straining]
[紧张]
In your face, Krabs.
在你的脸上，蟹蟹。
Ha!
哈!
[humming]
[嗡嗡声]
*
Krabs?
SpongeBoob?
螃蟹？
海绵布布？
Why aren't you in Dullsville?
你为什么不在杜尔斯维尔？
- We never left, Sheldon.
- 我们从未离开过，谢尔顿。
The Mr. Krabs and SpongeBoob
who followed the robot you
蟹老板和海绵宝宝
谁跟踪了你的机器人
to Dullsville
were also robots.
飞往杜尔斯维尔
也是机器人。
Gotcha.
[laughs]
明白了。
[笑]
- [grumbles]
Hate! Hate!
- [抱怨]
讨厌！恨！
Hate! Hate! Hate!
Hate! Hate!
恨！恨！恨！
恨！恨！
- So the way I see it,
Mr. Krabs and Plankton
- 所以在我看来，
蟹老板和浮游生物
are just using us as pawns in
their dumb secret formula war.
只是利用我们作为棋子
他们愚蠢的秘密公式战争。
- Agreed.
- 同意。
- Yeah, I mean,
who cares if that guy
- 是的，我的意思是，
谁在乎那个家伙
steals the secret
formula anyway?
窃取秘密
无论如何公式？
Grow up, that's what I say.
长大吧，这就是我说的。
- Agreed.
- 同意。
- So you're the real
Krabs and SpongeBob.
- 所以你才是真正的
蟹蟹和海绵宝宝。
Gimme that!
给我那个！
- Ooh.
- [yells]
- 哦。
- [大喊]
[all yelling, groaning]
[所有人大喊大叫，呻吟]
[phone rings]
- Yello.
[电话铃声]
- 耶罗。
Krusty Krab,
may I take your order?
蟹堡王,
我可以接受您的订单吗？
No, Mr. Krabs is unable
to come to the phone right now.
不，蟹老板不能
现在就来接电话。
He's trapped in
a dust cloud brawl.
他被困在
尘埃云斗殴。
Yeah, he'll have
to call you back.
是的，他会有
给你回电。
Gee, I hope our
robot look-alikes are okay.
哎呀，我希望我们的
机器人看起来很像还可以。
Bless their heart-like
pneumatic pumps.
祝福他们如心如意
气动泵。
[cheerful music]
[欢快的音乐]
*
all: Yay!
全体：耶！